ANCA PUSCASU

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

9	Montreal, Canada
	Open to Remote Work

- ancaa.puscasu@gmail.com
- ancapuscasu.web.app
- in linkedin.com/in/anca-puscasu
- github.com/ancapuscasu

PERSONAL PROFILE

Front-end developer (Javascript) with a background in psychology and social services. Experienced in collaborating with various stakeholders to come up with effective, productive and creative solutions. Skilled at understanding user's needs and creating products with them in mind.

FEATURED PROJECTS

myFlix | MERN & MEAN Application

A web app for movie enthusiasts to get information about movies, genres and directors. Users can edit their user details as well as create and edit a list of their favourite movies.

- API is built with REST architecture and uses HTTP and JWT authentication
- Responsive UI buit with Bootstrap and custom CSS
- Data validation on the front and back-end

Tech stack: React and Angular, MongoDB, Node.js and Express

ChatApp | Native Application

A mobile app that allows users to chat with each other. Users can pick a background color, read and send messages, share images and their location.

- Uses React Native Async Storage to store and retrieve messages when offline
- UI built with Gifted Chat library
- Uses Expo Location, ImagePicker and Permissions to access users devices and data
- Real-time data transfer using Cloud Firestore

Tech stack: React Native, Expo and Cloud Firestore

Meet Up | Serverless Progressive Web Application

A serverless web app for tech professionals to find upcoming networking and training events in their cities.

- Test-driven-development approach using Jest, Enzyme, Jest-Cucumber and Puppeteer
- Uses the Google Calendar API to fetch upcoming events and Google OAuth2 for authentication
- Data visualization using Recharts

Tech stack: React, Google Calendar API, AWS Lambda

ANCA PUSCASU

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Montreal, Canada ||
Open to Remote Work

ancaa.puscasu@gmail.com

ancapuscasu.web.app

in linkedin.com/in/anca-puscasu

github.com/ancapuscasu

EDUCATION

Intro to Frontend Development and Full Stack Immersion

CareerFoundry - Certificate

June 2021 - April 2022

 Intensive project-based online training program with a focus on MERN stack web applications

BA Psychology

University of British Columbia September 2013 - May 2018

 Minor in Health and Society - a multidisciplinary approach to health studies

WORK EXPERIENCE

Creator and Owner

Remane Domi Etsy Shop | January 2021 - July 2021

 Built custom products and managed customer service, operations and marketing for an online store selling wooden home decor and furniture pieces.

Child Care Program Support

YMCA | March 2018 - March 2020

- Monitored the needs of children from 15 classrooms and offered dynamic support with challenging behaviours and classroom management.
- Offered behavioural management expertise in the All Kids Belong program - promoting the inclusion of children with special needs into their classrooms.

Behaviour Interventionist

Self-Employed | June 2016 - January 2018

• Collaborated as part of a cross-functional team to develop and implement evidence based behaviour intervention plans for attaining therapy goals.